<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Flatiron | blog = true]]></title>
  <link href="http://mdorf85.github.io/blog/categories/flatiron/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mdorf85.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-03T00:01:10-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mdorf85.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Dorfman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mass Assignment: The Good, the Bad and the HOLY-MOTHER-OF-GOD-HACKER-INDUCED-NIGHTMARE]]></title>
    <link href="http://mdorf85.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/new-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-26T16:51:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mdorf85.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/new-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about Ruby&rsquo;s <strong>Mass Assignment</strong> feature.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Massignment&rdquo; as no one calls it to my knowledge, allows for the programmer to assign a mass number of things. Usually in a single step. Well, let&rsquo;s look at a few examples in the scope of just Ruby.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a thing you can do:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Massignment Ex. 1">a, b, c = 1, 2, 3
#=&gt;a = 1   b = 2   c = 3
</code></pre>

<p>Simple, intuitive and potentially useful.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s another thing one might do:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Massignment Ex. 2">abc_arr = (a, b, c = 1, 2, 3)
#=&gt;a = 1   b = 2   c = 3
#=&gt;abc_arr = [1, 2, 3]
</code></pre>

<p>Slightly less obvious. Well, this being Ruby, every operation yields a return value and mass assignment is no exception. As you can see, the assignment itself returns a value of the array of values that were assigned.</p>

<p>Neat.</p>

<p>Widening our scope from standalone Ruby console to any Rails-like environment, Mass Assignment takes on new roles. Particularly in the ever-relied on <code>params</code> hash in which values are assigned, for example, based on encoding in the URL of a HTTP GET request or from form data of a POST request.</p>

<p>So in the spirit of the latter, take a simple website form asking for the user&rsquo;s name that corresponds to a table with schema such as:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Massignment Ex. 3">t.string :name
t.boolean :admin, default: false, null: false
</code></pre>

<p>Say in its corresponding Controller&rsquo;s code, something like this line existed:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Massignment Ex. 3">@user = User.new(params[:user])
</code></pre>

<p>This means everything in the <code>params</code> hash will be mass assigned to the available attributes. An ill-intentioned user then might suspect - based on strong Rails conventions - that an <code>admin</code> attribute might exist and submit to the name form something roughly like:</p>

<p><form action="none" method="get">
  Name: <input type="text" name="example" value="user[name]=hacker&user[admin]=1" size="40" readonly><br>
</form></p>

<p>This could potentially be processed by the <code>params</code> hash as:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Massignment Ex. 3">params = {:name =&gt; "hacker", :admin =&gt; 1}
</code></pre>

<p>And well you get the idea. The user has set his <code>admin</code> privilege to <code>true</code> and that&rsquo;s a bad thing.</p>

<p>As it so happened, all this was pointed out as a vulnerability when in early 2012, Egor Homakov <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/github-suspends-member-over-mass-assignment-hack-4010025556/" target="_blank">more or less did this</a> on Github (a rails-based codebase). He gave himself the ability to commit a file to the Ruby on Rails project, and added some harmless files and <a href ="https://github.com/rails/rails/issues/5239" target-"_blank">posts</a> before Github acted and eventually publicly thanked him for his illumination of the issue.</p>

<p>It was all kind of like:</p>

<p><img src="http://img-9gag-lol.9cache.com/photo/5262242_700b_v1.jpg"></p>

<p>Anyway that was all a couple years ago which in the coding world is like a couple lightyears ago and so solutions and fixes that I&rsquo;m likely not even aware of have near-vanquished this bug.  One simple mitigation is making use of the <code>attr_protected</code> tool which specifies what fields may <strong>never</strong> be mass-assigned. You can also use its opposite <code>attr_accessible</code>, which allows you to list those attributes that can be mass-assigned.</p>

<p>Futhermore, incorporating a gem known as <a href="https://github.com/rails/strong_parameters">Strong Parameters</a> will include these protections in your Model/Controller.</p>

<p>So yeah, Mass Assignment is an example of something that on the outside is a total intuitive timesaver, but as we learned:</p>

<p>&ldquo;&hellip;with great convenience comes great potential for a total fucking meltdown.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Or something.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Law And/&amp;&amp; Order]]></title>
    <link href="http://mdorf85.github.io/blog/2014/10/13/law-and-slash-and-and-order/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T15:20:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mdorf85.github.io/blog/2014/10/13/law-and-slash-and-and-order</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Something that affects nearly every line of code you write, but tends not to receive too much attention is <strong>precedence</strong>, or the order in which operators are evaluated. Maybe that&rsquo;s because it&rsquo;s a somewhat cut and dry subject. What I mean by that is, once you know or reference this&hellip;</p>

<p><a href="http://ruby-doc.org/core-2.1.3/doc/syntax/precedence_rdoc.html">Ruby&rsquo;s Table of Precedence</a></p>

<p>&hellip;you&rsquo;re kind of all set.</p>

<p>But that doesn&rsquo;t mean moments won&rsquo;t arise when your code isn&rsquo;t working the way you&rsquo;d like and precedence ends up being the culprit.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a simple assignment example where you might expect one thing, but get something totally different:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Ex. 1 "and versus &&"">a = 2 and b = 4
puts "a = #{a}   b = #{b}"
#=&gt;a = 2   b = 4
</code></pre>

<p>Ok, sure. But what about this?</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Ex. 2 "and versus &&"">a = 2 &amp;&amp; b = 4
puts "a = #{a}   b = #{b}"
#=&gt;a = 4   b = 4
</code></pre>

<p>Woah&hellip;different.</p>

<p>Well, it makes perfect sense if you refer to your handy table of order of precedence. Here is what happens chronologically in Ex. 1:</p>

<p>1) the value 2 is assigned to the variable &lsquo;a&rsquo;<br>
2) the value 4 is assgined to the variable &lsquo;b&rsquo;</p>

<p>or</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Ex. 1 Expressed parenthetically">(a = 2) and (b = 4)
</code></pre>

<p>Since &lsquo;=&rsquo; has a greater precedence than &lsquo;and&rsquo; this makese sense.</p>

<p>In Ex. 2:</p>

<p>1) the value 4 is assigned to the variable &lsquo;b&rsquo;<br>
2) &lsquo;2 &amp;&amp; 4&rsquo; is evaluated, returning 4<br>
3) the value 4 is assigned to the variable &lsquo;a&rsquo;</p>

<p>or</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Ex. 2 Expressed parenthetically">a = (2 &amp;&amp; (b = 4))
a = (2 &amp;&amp; 4) #simplified
</code></pre>

<p>Once again it all comes down to &lsquo;&amp;&amp;&rsquo; having a higher order of precedence than &lsquo;=&rsquo; whereas that of &lsquo;and&rsquo; is lower than that of &lsquo;=&rsquo;.</p>

<p>In step 2 in Example 2 you&rsquo;ll notice that &lsquo;2 &amp;&amp; 4&rsquo; returns &lsquo;4&rsquo;. That is due to the <strong>Associativity</strong> of &lsquo;&amp;&amp;&rsquo; which is left-to-right. This means &lsquo;2&rsquo; is evaluated first, followed by &lsquo;4&rsquo; which is returned.</p>

<p>Finally, here&rsquo;s another quirk you might come across in Ruby&rsquo;s precedence rules:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Ex. 1 "&&/|| vs and/or"">true or true and false
#=&gt;false
</code></pre>

<p>while</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Ex. 2 "&&/|| vs and/or"">true || true &amp;&amp; false
#=&gt;true
</code></pre>

<p>The difference in return values here boils down to &lsquo;and&rsquo; and &lsquo;or&rsquo; having identical precedence resulting in Ruby evaluating it left-to-right while &lsquo;&amp;&amp;&rsquo; having a higher precedence than &lsquo;||&rsquo; means &lsquo;true &amp;&amp; false&rsquo; receives first evaluation resulting in a &lsquo;true || false&rsquo; that returns true.</p>

<p>In precedence, as with everything else in Ruby there are no surprises, so long as you know what to expect.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Post on Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://mdorf85.github.io/blog/2014/10/01/my-first-post-on-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-01T22:38:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mdorf85.github.io/blog/2014/10/01/my-first-post-on-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Hello World!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
